Guide to the Reproductive Health Ephemera Collection, 1968-2009 and undated RL.11334
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Reproductive Health Ephemera Collection
1968-2009 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11334
0.5 Linear Feet
The Reproductive Health Ephemera Collection Ephemera Collection consists of pamphlets, flyers, brochures, booklets, bumper stickers and other items that document the work of organizations concerned with women's reproductive health and reproductive rights. Collections contains items from both pro-choice and pro-life organizations.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Reproductive Health Ephemera Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase from 2012 to 2016.
Collection Overview
The Reproductive Health Ephemera Collection includes pamphlets, newsletters, flyers, booklets, bumper stickers, and other miscellany from a range of organizations and events related to abortion rights, sexual health, and reproductive health care. Collection contains items from both pro-choice and pro-life organizations. Collection is arranged chronologically. Most items are foldered individually with titles listed below.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Reproductive Heatlh Ephemera Collection was acquired piecemeal by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, beginning in 2013.
Pro-choice movement -- United States; Pro-life movement -- United States; Sterilization (Birth control); Reproductive health; Abortion counseling -- United States; Teenagers -- Sexual behavior -- United States; Reproductive rights -- United States; Planned Parenthood Federation of America; NARAL Pro-Choice America
- American Medical Association contraceptive pill brochure, 1970 (Box 1)
- Planned Parenthood World Population brochures, no. 401, 1968 and no. 771, 1970 (Box 1)
- Photograph, "LaSalle Street is Expecting," n.d., ca. 1970s (Box 1)
- Illinois Citizens for the Medical Control of Abortion, newsletter, 1970 (Box 1)
- Feminist Women's Health Center Self-Help Clinic, Oakland, CA, three newsletter articles, 1971 (Box 1)
- University of Michigan, "Contraceptive information and counseling," brochure, ca. 1972 (Box 1)
- Rocky Mountain Planned Parenthood, teen health brochures, 1973 (Box 1)
- NARAL, "Do you want to return to the butchery of back-alley abortion?," brochure, n.d., ca. 1973 (Box 1)
- Planned Parenthood New York, "Voluntary Sterilization for Men and Women," pamphlet, 1974 (Box 1)
- Berkeley Women's Health Collective brochure, 1975 (Box 1)
- "We Can't Stop Now," flyer, 1976 (Box 1)
- NOW San Jose Chapter, Sterilization Abuse fact sheet, 1977 (Box 1)
- Ad Hoc Committee for Abortion Rights, flyer, 1977 (Box 1)
- Coalition for Abortion Rights and Against Sterilization Abuse (CARASA), Buffalo, NY, flyer, 1979 (Box 1)
- "Women Beware! This is not a real clinic!" bumper sticker, 1980 (Box 1)
- Cleveland Pro-Choice Action Committee, Teenage Sexuality brochure, ca. 1980s (Box 1)
- Federation of Feminist Women's Health Centers, "Quackery in Gynecology: a Feminist Exposure", 1981 (Box 1)
- Youngs Drug Products Corporation, "Condoms and Human Sexuality" pamphlet, undated (Box 1)
- Alliance Against Women's Oppression, flyer, 1981 (Box 1)
- San Francisco Women's Centers, Abortion Rights Rally flyer, 1982 (Box 1)
- Last Days Ministeries, "The Crime of Being Alive: Abortion, Euthanasia, and Infanticide" brochure, 1984 (Box 1)
- "The Right and Responsibility to Rescue," booklet, Rev. Daniel J. Little, 1986 (Box 1)
- Coral Ridge Ministries, "Abortion: Cry of Reality," booklet, D. James Kennedy, 1989 (Box 1)
- Reproductive Health Technologies Project, The Use of Methotrexate for Early Abortion, conference packet, 1995 (Box 1)
- Abortion Conversation Project, "Our Truths/Nuestras Verdades" zine, no. 1 and no. 2, 2005 (Box 1)
- Revolution Talk, flyer, 2009 (Box 1)
- NOW East Bay, Golden Gate, Pro-choice flyer, n.d. (Box 1)
- Bay Area Coalition for Our Reproductive Rights (BACORR) bumper sticker, n.d. (Box 1)
- Juan Diego Society: Women's Center in San Jose, Legion of Mary, Pro-Life Work Prayer Guide, n.d. (Box 1)
- Chicago Area Clergy Consultation Service, unwanted pregnancy brochure, n.d. (Box 1)
- Youngs Drug Products Corporation, "Condoms and Human Sexuality" pamphlet, undated (Box 1)
- PFOC "Our Bodies, Our lives" poster (Oversize-folder 1)